Fuwen TAN

Contact 85 Engineer's Way

85 Engineer's Way fuwen.tan@virginia.edu Rice Hall 420, PO Box 400740 Phone: (434)4660099

Charlottesville, VA 22904 http://www.cs.virginia.edu/~ft3ex/

Summary

I am a Ph.D. student in the Computer Science Department of University of Virginia (U.Va.), working with Dr. Vicente Ordóñez Román. My research interests are in computer vision, natural language processing and graphics. More recently, I am especially interested in learning interpretable representations of human knowledge from visual data and language. I'm also interested in building intelligent systems for visual content retrieval and generation.

Before joining the Ph.D. program in U.Va., I was a Research Associate at the BeingThere center of Nanyang Technological University, working on Computer Graphics and 3D Telepresence. I graduated from Sun-Yat sen University with a B.S. degree in Mathematics.

EDUCATION

University of Virginia

Ph.D. Program in Computer Science Advisor: Vicente Ordóñez Román

Zhejiang UniversityM.S.in Mathematics
Advisor: Ligang Liu

Hangzhou, China
Sep.2010 - Jun.2012

Sun Yat-sen University B.S. in Mathematics

Guangzhou, China Sep.2006 - Jun.2010

Charlottesville, United States

Aug.2015 - Present

RESEARCH

Text2Scene: Generating Abstract Scenes from Textual Descriptions

Fuwen Tan, Song Feng, Vicente Ordonez

arXiv preprint, 2018.

Where and Who? Automatic Semantic-Aware Person Composition

Fuwen Tan, Crispin Bernier, Benjamin Cohen, Vicente Ordonez, Connelly Barnes IEEE Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision (WACV), 2018

FaceCollage: A Rapidly Deployable System for Real-time Head Reconstruction for On-The-Go 3D Telepresence

Fuwen Tan, Chi-Wing Fu, Teng Deng, Jianfei Cai, Tat Jen Cham

ACM Multimedia (ACM MM, full paper), 2017

High-Quality Kinect Depth Filtering For Real-time 3D Telepresence Mengyao Zhao, **Fuwen Tan**, Chi-Wing Fu, Chi-Keung Tang, Jianfei Cai, Tat Jen Cham

IEEE International Conference on Multimedia and Expo (ICME), 2013

Field-Guided Registration for Feature-Conforming Shape Composition Hui Huang, Minglun Gong, Daniel Cohen-Or, Yaobin Ouyang, **Fuwen Tan**, Hao Zhang SIGGRAPH ASIA, 2012

EXPERIENCE

Amazon A9, Palo Alto, United States

May.2018 - Aug.2018

Applied scientist intern in Visual Search & AR team

Design and implement a working solution for an improved image segmentation approach for creation

of AR models.

Manager: Sundar Vedular; Mentor: Tony Hwang

Honda Research Institute, Mountain View, United States

May.2016 - Aug.2016

Research intern in Perception Group

Research on application of Deep Learning to traffic participant detection.

Manager: Bernd Heisele

Nanyang Technological University, Singapore

Aug.2012 - Jul.2015

Research Associate at BeingThere Centre, Institute for Media Innovation

Design and implement a low-cost, fast and realistic system for personal 3D telepresence.

Supervisor: Chi-Wing Fu

AWARDS

Merit Poster Award in GPU Technology Workshop South East Asia (GTW-SEA), 2014

Honor Graduate of Sun Yat-sen University, 2010

Freshman Scholarship of Sun Yat-sen University, 2006

Score#1 in Yangjiang, Guangdong, on China's National Higher Education Entrance Examination

Professional

Teaching Assistants

Services

CS1113 (Programming), CS2150 (Data Structure)

CS4457 (Computer Networks), CS4810 (Computer Graphics)

CS6501 (Computational Visual Recognition)

Aug.2015 - Dec.2015

Jan.2016 - May.2016

Aug.2016 - Dec.2016

Reviewer

IEEE Transactions on Image Processing (TIP)

2017